India
Marist Archives and Special Collections
India
2.1.3.1.1.7
Marist College
  Box 1501
- India, 2.1.3.1.1.7
  - India, 1921-1922; 57 (Box 1501)
    - Snake charmer, 1
    - Verso: Snake charmer - good., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 58 (Box 1501)
    - Snake charmer and Lowell Thomas wearing pith helmet and holding a cane [3 copies], 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas watched with interest the performance an Indian snake-charmer. The picture was taken while Thomas was with the Prince of Wales in India in 1922, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 59 (Box 1501)
    - Karachi, Frere Hall, better view of baggage in carts drawn by camels and donkeys, 1
    - Verso: Freear Hall- baggage (best view of baggage), 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 60 (Box 1501)
    - Lowell Thomas and wife, Frances Ryan Thomas, on camel, 1
    - Verso: Tommy and me, 1-verso
    - Lowell Thomas and wife, Frances Ryan Thomas, on camel, 2
    - Verso: Mr + Mrs. L.T. on camel, 2-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 61 (Box 1501)
    - Young married couple, boy, age fourteen, girl, age eight, close-up, 1
    - Verso: Young married couple closeup., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 62 (Box 1501)
    - Pink Mountains of Baluchistan, ridge like waterfall, automobile in foreground [3 copies], 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 63 (Box 1501)
    - Looking toward Kojak Pass from east [3 copies], 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 64 (Box 1501)
    - Nomad tent and family, 1
    - Verso: Nomad tent + family., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 65 (Box 1501)
    - Nomad tent and family, Lowell Thomas on left, camel in foreground, 1
    - Verso: Nomad tent + family - L.T. on left, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 66 (Box 1501)
    - Chuman Fort, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 67 (Box 1501)
    - Afghan man with sheep [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: A Beluchi shepherd, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 68 (Box 1501)
    - Two Afghans talking, 1
    - Verso: Afghan tribesmen discussing crops, and blood feuds in the bazaar at Quetta [2 copies], 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 69 (Box 1501)
    - Old Afghan carrying stick, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 70 (Box 1501)
    - Quetta main bazaar street [3 copies], 1
    - Verso: Quetta - main bazaar street, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 71 (Box 1501)
    - Tibetan person sitting on wall, 1
    - Verso: Tibetan person seated on wall, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 72 (Box 1501)
    - Chinese Turkestan "type", 1
    - Verso: Chinese Turkestan "type", 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 73 (Box 1501)
    - Merchant selling grain [3 copies], 1
    - Verso: Selling grain in the Quetta bazaar, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 74 (Box 1501)
    - Two old men talking [4 copies], 1
    - Verso: A Quetta cobbler invites his customer to have a whiff from his hooka, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 75 (Box 1501)
    - "Old Father Abraham" [4 copies], 1
    - Verso: "Old Father Abraham", 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 76 (Box 1501)
    - Quetta market, 1
    - Verso: Quetta market, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 77 (Box 1501)
    - Modern village in Taxila, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 78 (Box 1501)
    - Valley where ancient city of Taxila was located, this part is nearest mountains [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: (caption) - The valley near Rawal Pindi where Sir John Marshall is uncovering one of the richest archeological mines in the world - the ancient city of Taxila, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 79 (Box 1501)
    - Taxila, remains of large stupa, 1
    - Verso: Taxila, remains of large stupa, 1-verso
  Box 1502
- India, 2.1.3.1.1.7
  - India, 1921-1922; 1 (Box 1502)
    - Taxila, small, perfect stupa, man in foreground, 1
    - Verso: (caption) - A small but perfect ancient Buddhist Stupa uncovered at Taxila, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 2 (Box 1502)
    - Bridge over Indus at Attock, 1
    - Verso: Bridge over Indus at Attock, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 3 (Box 1502)
    - Man sitting on Kim's gun [Zamzama gun], "guru" standing in foreground, Lahore, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 4 (Box 1502)
    - Two Sikhs, Kim's gun [Zamzama gun], Lahore, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 5 (Box 1502)
    - One Sikh, Kim's gun [Zamzama gun], Lahore, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 6 (Box 1502)
    - Nankana Sahib shrine, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 7 (Box 1502)
    - Nankana Sahib shrine, Sikh sitting in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 8 (Box 1502)
    - Amritsar Golden Temple, seen through gate, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 9 (Box 1502)
    - Amritsar Golden Temple, lake in foreground, minaret in background, 1
    - Verso: Amritsar Golden Temple,water and one tower, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 10 (Box 1502)
    - Amritsar Golden Temple, clock tower, 1
    - Verso: Amritsar Golden Temple, clock tower, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 11 (Box 1502)
    - Amritsar Golden Temple, lake, two minarets, 1
    - Verso: Amritsar Golden Temple, water, two minarets, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 12 (Box 1502)
    - Scene of Amritsar shooting episode led by Brigadier-General Reginald Dyer, 1
    - Verso: Jallumwalabad where General Dyer fired on mob, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 13 (Box 1502)
    - Great Mosque at Red Fort, Jama Masjid, herd of goats, 1
    - Verso: Great Mosque at Red Fort, herd of goats, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 14 (Box 1502)
    - Great Mosque at Red Fort, Jama Masjid, as seen through gate, 1
    - Verso: A dreamy mosque in Northern India, the chief place of worship for the Mahammedans of the great city of Lahore, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 15 (Box 1502)
    - Akbar Gate, fort, 1
    - Verso: Akbar Gate, Fort Lahore, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 16 (Box 1502)
    - Ranjit Singh pavilion, fort with Saman Burj in background, 1
    - Verso: Ranjit Singh pavilion, fort with Saman Burj in background, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 17 (Box 1502)
    - Pavilion of Ranjit Singh close-up, 1
    - Verso: Pavilion of Ranjit Singh close-up, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 18 (Box 1502)
    - Three Hindus covered with paint (reddish yellow) [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Three Hindus covered with reddish yellow paint. Hindu merrymakers and the state of their clothes at the conclusion of the festival, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 19 (Box 1502)
    - Elephant in front of mosque, Mr. and Mrs. Harry Chase and Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas sit atop the elephant, 1
    - Verso: Elephant in front of mosque. Mr. + Mrs. H.A.C. and Mrs. L.T., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 20 (Box 1502)
    - Delhi, Kashmir Gate, 1
    - Verso: Delhi, Kashmir Gate, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 21 (Box 1502)
    - Delhi, Great Mosque, 1
    - Verso: Cut out foreground and use one of our cloud negatives to make fine cloud effect above mosque, 1-verso
  - India, 1921; 22 (Box 1502)
    - Delhi, Great Mosque, 1
    - Verso: Delhi - Great Mosque. Not so good., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 23 (Box 1502)
    - Safdarjung's tomb, model for Taj Mahal, 1
    - Verso: A scene from "Romantic India," the Lowell Thomas film production which shows most of the beauty spots of Hindustan, glimpse of the life of the many races who live there, and all that is weird and wonderful in the strangest country in the world. One million people appear in this film production, scores of elephants, tigers, fakirs, and many weird sights, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 24 (Box 1502)
    - Alai Darwaza Gate to Qutub Minar, 1
    - Verso: Alai Darwaza - gate to Kutb Minar, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 25 (Box 1502)
    - Iron pillar, one arch, woman standing in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 26 (Box 1502)
    - Taj Mahal, view from gate, three women in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 27 (Box 1502)
    - Taj Mahal, side view, two trees in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 28 (Box 1502)
    - Taj Mahal across river, man in boat, 1
    - Verso: The Taj from across the Jumna, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 29 (Box 1502)
    - Taj Mahal across river, man on bank, 1
    - Verso: Taj - from across river - man on bank., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 30 (Box 1502)
    - Taj Mahal, side view, looking up river, 1
    - Verso: Taj - side view looking up river, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 31 (Box 1502)
    - Taj Mahal looking down river, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 32 (Box 1502)
    - Gate to Taj Mahal from outside, 1
    - Verso: Gate to Taj from outside, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 33 (Box 1502)
    - Flowers carved in marble, 1
    - Verso: Flowers carved in marble, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 34 (Box 1502)
    - Tomb inside Taj Mahal, 1
    - Verso: Tomb inside Taj, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 35 (Box 1502)
    - Carved marble screen [3 copies], 1
    - Verso: Carved marble screen, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 36 (Box 1502)
    - Looking into garden from tomb in Taj Mahal, 1
    - Verso: Looking into garden from tomb in Taj, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 37 (Box 1502)
    - Safdarjung's tomb through upper arch, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 38 (Box 1502)
    - Safdarjung's tomb with tree on right, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 39 (Box 1502)
    - Meerut, church near site of mutiny, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 40 (Box 1502)
    - Cawnpore well, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 41 (Box 1502)
    - Lucknow, gate to residency, 1
    - Verso: Lucknow - gate to residency, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 42 (Box 1502)
    - Lucknow residency, two men kneeling in road, 1
    - Verso: Residency - 2 men kneeling in road, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 43 (Box 1502)
    - Lucknow residency, white monument, 1
    - Verso Rwesidency + white monument, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 44 (Box 1502)
    - Lucknow residency, flag and ruins close [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Lucknow residency, flag and ruins close, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 45 (Box 1502)
    - Lucknow, United Service Club, distant, 1
    - Verso: United Service Club, Lucknow, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 46 (Box 1502)
    - Turkish Gate, Lucknow, 1
    - Verso: A great Mohammedan gateway in Lucknow, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 47 (Box 1502)
    - Wall of Imambara, Lucknow, 1
    - Verso: Wall of Imambara, Lucknow, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 48 (Box 1502)
    - Idol of sacred cow, Well of Knowledge, 1
    - Verso: The idol of the golden bull at Benares, one of the most famous places of worship in India. Lowell Thomas Travelogues, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 49 (Box 1502)
    - Benares cart, close-up, 1
    - Verso: Benares cart, close-up, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 50 (Box 1502)
    - Benares river scene, mosque reflection, 1
    - Verso: Benares, river scene Mosque reflection. The simple monotheistic minarets of Islam ride above the jumbled chaos of the hundreds of weird Hindu temples of Benares just as the simplicity of Muhammad's creed stands in striking contrast to the bewildering complexity of Hinduism, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 51 (Box 1502)
    - Museum and great stupa, 1
    - Verso: Museum and great stupa, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 52 (Box 1502)
    - Great stupa, close-up, 1
    - Verso: Great stupa, close-up, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 53 (Box 1502)
    - Darjeeling coolies, five girls and boys, 1
    - Verso: Five coolie girls and boys, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 54 (Box 1502)
    - Foundation for new Secretariat, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 55 (Box 1502)
    - Statues in yard, Jain Temple, 1
    - Verso: Statues in yard, Jain Temple, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 56 (Box 1502)
    - Jain Temple from yard, 1
    - Verso: Jain Temple from yard, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 57 (Box 1502)
    - Jain Temple water, man on steps, 1
    - Verso: Jain Temple, water, man on steps, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 58 (Box 1502)
    - Jain temple man standing straight in water, 1
    - Verso: Jain temple man standing straight in water, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 59 (Box 1502)
    - Jain Temple, man leaning over in water, 1
    - Verso: Temple, man leaning over in water, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 60 (Box 1502)
    - Two starving children, one with hand at neck, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 61 (Box 1502)
    - Hindu temple, Madras bazaar, without clouds, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 62 (Box 1502)
    - Hindu temple, Madras bazaar, with clouds, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 63 (Box 1502)
    - Interior of church, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 64 (Box 1502)
    - Painting above altar, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 65 (Box 1502)
    - Old silver service, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 66 (Box 1502)
    - Mrs. Annie Besant, standing, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 67 (Box 1502)
    - Mr. Knox, resident, Hyderabad, Mrs. Knox, Mr. Kirkbride and a lady, Hyderabad, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 68 (Box 1502)
    - Charminar, Hyderabad [2 copies], 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 69 (Box 1502)
    - Charminar with cart in foreground, Hyderabad, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 70 (Box 1502)
    - Tombs of Kings, panorama, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 71 (Box 1502)
    - There tombs, trees in foreground, Hyderabad [2 copies], 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 72 (Box 1502)
    - Tomb with dome and tomb with two minarets, Hyderabad, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 73 (Box 1502)
    - Tombs of Kings, women with water jars on heads, Hyderabad, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 74 (Box 1502)
    - Hyderabad Arab, right hand on chest, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 75 (Box 1502)
    - Old man holding chicken and cage, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 76 (Box 1502)
    - One of Nizam's Arab soldiers with walking stick, Hyderabad, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 77 (Box 1502)
    - Old man with white beard and moustache, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 78 (Box 1502)
    - Old beggar holding tin [2 copies], 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 79 (Box 1502)
    - Residency, Hyderabad [3 copies], 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 80 (Box 1502)
    - Lowell Thomas, Francis Yeats-Brown, Cape Comorin [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Looking out over an unbroken expanse of sea from India to the South Pole, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 81 (Box 1502)
    - Lowell Thomas, Francis Yeats-Brown, Cape Comorin, 1
    - Note: L.T. standing on a rock at the southernmost tip of the vast peninsula of Hindustan. This rock is called Cape Comoran. Very few travelers have been to this spot, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 82 (Box 1502)
    - Nagercoil Temple, tank and mountain, 1
    - Note: Hindu temples near the extreme southern tip of India, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 83 (Box 1502)
    - Two Dravidian boys standing, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 84 (Box 1502)
    - Two Indian Jesuit priests, 1
    - Verso: One black and one white, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 85 (Box 1502)
    - Smiling boy, palm umbrella, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 86 (Box 1502)
    - Two Brahmin priests, palm umbrellas [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Two Brahmin priests in Southern India. The Brahmins consider themselves to be half man and half god. They are at the top of the Hindu caste system. The penalty for sitting down beside a Brahmin is to have the sitting part removed and to strike a Brahmin is to incur thousand years of hell. If the shadow of a European or a low caste Indian falls across the food of a Brahmin he must throw it away because it is defiled, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 87 (Box 1502)
    - Canal, palms, boats, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 88 (Box 1502)
    - Jewish patriarch with cane, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 89 (Box 1502)
    - Jewish patriarch and two boys, 1
    - Verso: The two boys are darker skinned than the old man who is as white as an European old man, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 90 (Box 1502)
    - Calicut Hindu [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: A Malabar Knut one of the "mild" Hindoos of the West Coast whom the Moplalis failed to convert. A Hindu of the Malabar Coast, 1-verso
  Box 1503
- India, 2.1.3.1.1.7
  - India, 1921-1922; 1 (Box 1503)
    - Moplah with black beard, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 2 (Box 1503)
    - Boy with caste mark and big teeth, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 3 (Box 1503)
    - Youth, large caste marks on body, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 4 (Box 1503)
    - Man with big turban, caste mark and scraggly beard [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Follower of Vishnu with the trident on his forehead. Between the two white prongs is a thin red one which is not distinguishable in the picture, Copyright by Lowell Thomas, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 5 (Box 1503)
    - Brahmin wearing muffler, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 6 (Box 1503)
    - Man with bushy hair and wide horizontal caste marks, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 7 (Box 1503)
    - Crowd of bullock carts [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Bullock carts and pilgrims in the bed of the river on the outskirts of Madura. In the distance looms the great temple, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 8 (Box 1503)
    - Lowell Thomas and Francis Yeats-Brown standing under banyan tree, 1
    - Note: L.T. and Major Yeats Brown standing beneath a small portion of the famous Calcutta banyan tree, said to be the largest tree in the world. All of the verdure to be seen in this picture is a part of the one tree, and not more than a tenth of it is visible from this angle., 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 9 (Box 1503)
    - One tower, palms in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 10 (Box 1503)
    - One tower of temple and street, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 11 (Box 1503)
    - Trichinopoly rock and water tank without pavilion, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 12 (Box 1503)
    - Temple gate, women with backs to camera, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 13 (Box 1503)
    - Tanjore temple, Lowell Thomas and other man in foreground [2 copies], 1
    - Note: L.T. standing in the courtyard of the Great Temple in Madura, one of the wonders of Asia, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 14 (Box 1503)
    - Tanjore bull, 1
    - Verso: Light grey stone with red stripes running up and down part of it, 1-verso
  - India, 15 (Box 1503)
    - Two women praying before Lingam, 1
    - Note: Hindu women, in southern India, praying for children, in front of phallic shrine, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 16 (Box 1503)
    - Carts loaded with water jars, 1
    - Verso: Jars are bright brick red. Building of slightly reddish sandstone but much of it dark grey from age, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 17 (Box 1503)
    - Pondicherry gods, 1
    - Verso: Ayannar - the god who rides by night - Make up and down cut of 3 principal figures, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 18 (Box 1503)
    - Two Pondicherry gods, young person in foreground, 1
    - Verso: White statues with bright red, blue, and green eyebrows, hair, mustache, etc., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 19 (Box 1503)
    - Five toddy tappers, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 20 (Box 1503)
    - Pondicherry well, walking beam, close-up, 1
    - Note: the primitive device for raising water from a well to an irrigation ditch. The native holding the pole near the right of the picture, fills the bucket. The men on the teetering beam walk up and down in a way that raises the bucket to the height of the irrigation ditch. They walk up and down like this day in and day out, in the broiling sun, and receive for their labor the handsome honorarium of two cents a day, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 21 (Box 1503)
    - Pondicherry well, walking beam, distant, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 22 (Box 1503)
    - Goa Cathedral, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 23 (Box 1503)
    - Government house, Madras district, close-up, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 24 (Box 1503)
    - University Hall, Madras, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 25 (Box 1503)
    - Temple and street, 1
    - Verso: Make cut for book, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 26 (Box 1503)
    - Brahmin with umbrella, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 27 (Box 1503)
    - Fakir with yak tail fan, 1
    - Note: A temple attendant. This man walks in front of the god, driving away the flies from the holy face by waving a Sacred Cow's tail. His matted hair is dressed with Holy Cow manure, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 28 (Box 1503)
    - Two sacred bulls, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 29 (Box 1503)
    - Jagannath Temple, two Jagannath (Juggernaut) cars, great crowd of people, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 30 (Box 1503)
    - One Jagannath (Juggernaut) car on the move, very near view, 1
    - Verso: The world-famous car of Juggernaut. Once each year the god, Juggernaut, most widely known of all Hindu idols, is placed in this car and taken for a ride, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 31 (Box 1503)
    - Jagannath (Juggernaut) car on boulevard, distant, 1
    - Note: The car of Juggernaut in the midst of its journey. Here are about five hundred thousand people taking part in the event. They all attempt to get hold of the ropes in order to pull the car. The Hindus call Juggernaut "God of the World", 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 32 (Box 1503)
    - Captain Guise and assistant, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 33 (Box 1503)
    - Lowell Thomas in palki, 1
    - Verso: Make cut for book, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 34 (Box 1503)
    - Black Pagoda, Lowell Thomas in palki, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 35 (Box 1503)
    - Dragons guarding Black Pagoda, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 36 (Box 1503)
    - Wheel of Black Pagoda, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 37 (Box 1503)
    - Four carved images, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 38 (Box 1503)
    - Sun god standing, woman kneeling at feet, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 39 (Box 1503)
    - Sun god, one hand gone, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 40 (Box 1503)
    - Dancing girl statue, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 41 (Box 1503)
    - Lowell Thomas, two people of the Criminal Tribes, hut, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 42 (Box 1503)
    - Hut and family of the people of the Criminal Tribes, 1
    - Verso: Very black people, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 43 (Box 1503)
    - Lathia fighter, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 44 (Box 1503)
    - Chief of the people of the Criminal Tribes, full length, 1
    - Verso: Man almost as black as a negro, 1-verso
    - Note: Chief Ankatigadu, known as "the man who stole six policemen," because he captures six native cops, disrobed them, put their uniforms on himself and companions, and then went up and down the country, robbing more than ever, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 45 (Box 1503)
    - Bengal Club, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 46 (Box 1503)
    - Black Hole monument, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 47 (Box 1503)
    - Black Hole monument, Lowell Thomas in distance, 1
    - Note: This iron fence encloses the spot famous in history as "the Black Hole of Calcutta." The palace of an Indian prince stood here long years ago. In it was a room the exact size of this enclosure, in which the Rajah imprisoned nearly two hundred Europeans. When the door was opened the next morning most of them were dead from suffocation. That tragedy led to one of the ten decisive battles in the history of the world, the Battle of Plassey, where Clive overthrew the Moghul emperor, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 48 (Box 1503)
    - Rabindranath Tagore, seated, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 49 (Box 1503)
    - C.F. Andrews, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 50 (Box 1503)
    - Fat man and French professor, 1
    - Verso: Three instructors at Rabindrinath Tagor's school. The bearded gentleman on the left is a Frenchman from the Sorbonne, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 51 (Box 1503)
    - Rabindranath Tagore, on steps, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 52 (Box 1503)
    - Abanindranath Tagore and Gaganendranath Tagore in garden, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 53 (Box 1503)
    - Dwijendranath Tagore, eldest of Tagore brothers, close-up, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 54 (Box 1503)
    - Clouds and green valley, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 55 (Box 1503)
    - Clouds and mountain tops, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 56 (Box 1503)
    - Lowell Thomas and other man reading in a train sleeper compartment, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 57 (Box 1503)
    - Lama with distorted face, nearer view, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 58 (Box 1503)
    - Lama with prayer wheel sitting on rock, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 59 (Box 1503)
    - Lama holding prayer wheel and staff, dagger in belt, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 60 (Box 1503)
    - Smiling lama with scraggly beard, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 61 (Box 1503)
    - River steamer, two small boats in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 62 (Box 1503)
    - Row boat, two men, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 63 (Box 1503)
    - Boat, sail up, two men poling, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 64 (Box 1503)
    - Man with grey beard, long hair on chest, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 65 (Box 1503)
    - Sir Henry Lawrence's Grave, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 66 (Box 1503)